<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-09T23:15:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Five Weeks Abroad</title><subtitle>Life in a new place... for a little while</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The One Where We Bought Bad Cheese</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/the-one-where-we-bought-the-bad-cheese" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We Bought Bad Cheese" /><published>2017-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/the-one-where-we-bought-the-bad-cheese</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/the-one-where-we-bought-the-bad-cheese">&lt;p&gt;We made it to Malaga Friday morning after a short flight from Barcelona. Ryan was awestruck by the floor cleaning techniques at the Barcelona airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3ov9k0ap6XEgjUoplC/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Gif Of Lady Zooming By&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penny got to ride outside her carrier for all but five minutes of the flight. Here she is begging to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/penny_in_carrier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny in carrier on airplane&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, she doesn’t make a peep, but I’m guessing she couldn’t contain her excitement either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we got into Malaga before the Airbnb was ready, we dropped our bags off and headed for a stroll around town. We found out that Churros y Chocolate are as prominent in Malaga as Starbucks in a college town. Clearly, we had to stop for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/churro_time.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Churro Time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few times does a plan go so perfectly for non-Type A people, such as us, that we must pat ourselves on the back. So far, this was the whole trip here but the cherry on top is finding our Airbnb. Look at this beauty. Here is Ryan again for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/ryan_apartment.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan in apartment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s even got Penny’s seal of approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/penny_on_couch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny on couch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were settled into the apartment, we decided to go back out to get our bearings down. We walked to Old Town and noticed most stores were closed and not a lot of people were out and about. It was too early in the day for siesta, and just another Friday. We thought maybe it was a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/empty_promenade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Empty town promenade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were correct. The town of Malaga was celebrating their patron saint, the Santa Maria de la Victoria, credited by King Ferdinand for winning back the city from the Moors in 1487. We encountered the long procession where the (massive) statue is carried back to the cathedral at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/packed_promenade(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Packed town promenade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we walked to el Mercado de Atarazanas, after my dad’s suggestions of the market from a Youtube video. There we found fresh seafood (mariscos), vegetables (verduras), y queso Manchego. Also a TON of Marcona almonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/almonds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;So many almonds!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I snatched up some Manchego cheese and jamon Iberico with much excitement. The cheese cost € 4 and I was pumped to for this treat to my palate. We had an early dinner to include the cheese. And to much dissatisfaction, I found out that either I had bought the wrong cheese, or this was the real version of Spanish Manchego that I now had to adapt to. It had was very similar to blue cheese and I don’t know about you, but that’s where I draw the line on my love of queso. Something about that awful sour mold taste is not appealing. I’m just glad we didn’t drop € 15 on that bad boy. This is how you travel though, throwing caution to the wind. Like that time I bought a whole wedge of unpasteurized cheese in London, without ever having had something so dangerous and unregulated, and didn’t die! Wouldn’t be writing this if I had…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/manchego.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Manchego Cheese&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html">We made it to Malaga Friday morning after a short flight from Barcelona. Ryan was awestruck by the floor cleaning techniques at the Barcelona airport.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where We Get to Spain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We Get to Spain" /><published>2017-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain">&lt;p&gt;The incredible forces of jetlag have me writing this at 3:42am on this fine Friday morning. This is after having stared at the ceiling of our tiny hotel room for 2 hrs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Spain unscathed after the hottest plane ride of my life. Something about that stale airplane air, the hundreds of bodies surrounding us, and Penny’s body heat made for an uncomfortable flight. Someday we’ll fly in the comfort of First or Business class; but what’s flying to Europe without making you work for it?  After eleven hours from Los Angeles we landed in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully getting into Spain with Penny was surprisingly simple. Once through border patrol, we had a quick examination of Penny’s health certificate and a scan of her ID chip and she was cleared to go. We picked up our bags and grabbed a taxi to the hotel.
Our tiny hotel room in Barcelona. Okay, so this demands photographic evidence to really show how small this room is. Conveniently, I’ve got my handy-dandy 6 foot 4 hubby for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogTiny1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Hotel Room 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogTiny2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Hotel Room 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we’re only here for a night. We had to fly direct from the US into Spain in order to get Penny in the cabin with us, through the fabulous Norwegian Airlines (more on this in a future post). So that left flying into Barcelona for far less than directly into Malaga or Madrid. Anyway, we will be getting to our destination in Malaga later today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there isn’t much to say about Barcelona considering our short stay here. We arrived deliriously jetlagged, hungry and in great need of a shower. Once we got our needs sorted, we went out to find some dinner. The hotel is right off the now infamous Las Ramblas street; which we walked down to find some tapas in the form of meatballs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/Blogmeatballs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meatballs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some delicious Spanish fusion meatballs, we tackled a light drizzle back to the hotel. Penny then had the LONGEST pee ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/Blogpee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny Pee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her poor bladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only place you might find a mere essence of happiness at LAX is within the Tom Bradley International Terminal. Ryan and I first experienced this beautiful terminal thanks to a flight to MIA that had an international connection to Heathrow. Finally, we were more than plebeians trudging along the horrid TSA line; we had found mecca. And now we were back! This time with Priority Pass lounge access via Chase Sapphire!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogLounge1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Access&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penny ate the finest mediocre sushi and enjoyed views of the sheeple down below. Did I mention they had an unattended bar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogLounge2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Drinks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of Ferris Bueller, “It’s so choice. If you have the means, I highly recommend picking one up.” Of course, he’s talking about a vintage Ferrari and I’m referencing a piece of plastic with amazing travel bonuses– but, to each their own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><summary type="html">The incredible forces of jetlag have me writing this at 3:42am on this fine Friday morning. This is after having stared at the ceiling of our tiny hotel room for 2 hrs…</summary></entry></feed>