<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-11T10:34:41-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Analog Drives</title><subtitle>Driving Matters</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Subaru Hates Enthusiasts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/09/subaru-hates-enthusiasts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Subaru Hates Enthusiasts" /><published>2017-06-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/09/subaru-hates-enthusiasts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/09/subaru-hates-enthusiasts">&lt;p&gt;Not only have Subaru managed to produce better cars that get better gas mileage with better safety ratings; they have also gotten better at selling cars too. Incentives are amongst the lowest in the segment for key models and often sales are constrained by production. Day supply and fleet are both low. Odds are if you’re still reading this you’re an enthusiast and it fresh on your mind since you most likely helped your parents cross-shop a Forester with a CX-5 for them lately. Somewhere along your research you must have noticed what I noticed, Subaru is not what it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have gone from a niche product lineup that was the cool Tacoma alternative in mountain towns across North America to being the premier outdoorsy yuppie-mobile on sale today. Nothing says I like to go be outdoorsy sometimes like a Subaru. Who cares if they only take it car camping once a year at a campground they made reservations at to pay $40 a night to sleep on a gravel square in a specific place in the woods with neighbors chanting “USA“ at midnight while they think about what wildlife might eat m; but they go camping dammint because they drive a Subaru!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some where along the line Subaru lost its most lived-out-of car image in favor of gingham dress shirts and flexible work schedules. Even the WRX has officially stopped racing in the series it was named for then got neutered with a CVT.  Now that the WRX cares about fuel economy and to helping short attention-spanned tech-duches afraid to learn how to use an extra pedal get a sweet $299 lease deal on there dream car. Moral of the story Subaru has focused on everyone but there most loyal and enthusiast fan base; they have sold out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Steve Makuch</name></author><summary type="html">Not only have Subaru managed to produce better cars that get better gas mileage with better safety ratings; they have also gotten better at selling cars too. Incentives are amongst the lowest in the segment for key models and often sales are constrained by production. Day supply and fleet are both low. Odds are if you’re still reading this you’re an enthusiast and it fresh on your mind since you most likely helped your parents cross-shop a Forester with a CX-5 for them lately. Somewhere along your research you must have noticed what I noticed, Subaru is not what it used to be.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Frustrations of Driving a Car With The Engine in the Right Place</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/08/the-frustrations-of" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Frustrations of Driving a Car With The Engine in the Right Place" /><published>2017-06-08T23:07:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-06-08T23:07:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/08/the-frustrations-of</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/06/08/the-frustrations-of">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/fiata_front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fiat 124 Spider&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a past Porsche 911 owner, which I don’t seem to miss an opportunity to mention, I have a slightly different outlook and expectation of a driving experience. While strange at first, I became accustomed to the engine in the back, the practice of get all your breaking done before the corner and maintain speed through the corner so you don’t upset balance and end up with your ass giving the directions, accelerate just after apexing and the front of the car will bite, the diff will engage trimming the line, and the car will rocket off. This style of driving was a blast and I learned to love it. Whenever Steve would ride with me, he would always get a little uncomfortable when I was driving, odds say that’s because I’m a crap driver, but he insists the way I did my cornering made him think I was going to understeer off the side of a properly tall mountain. It was just how rear engine cars drove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been driving a few different small roadsters, the last two being an ND  MX-5 Miata Sport and a base Fiat 124 Spider. Though the ND had the nice high performance bits and a superior suspension tune, my experience in both cars was shockingly similar: Frustration. I hop in the drivers seat, rev the nuts off the engine and get going, preparing myself for this transcendental experience that every automotive journalist and fanboy clamours over, and here I am screaming obsceneties to myself asking why it’s so twitchy and understeering in the corners! I would like to take a minute here to step back and say, as later me will find out, these cars are fantastically capable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said they’re not hop-in-and-go-fast cars. There’s a real acclimation period to these things. The first thing to click was that my braking was all screwy, I needed to brake as little as possible and trail brake into the apex. This was a world changing realization, suddenly the understeer is gone, the nose is pointy and the body is rotating like I wanted it to. Not to say that trail braking is no good in a rear engined car, but I had heard such horror stories about messing with the car balance mid-corner that I had honestly never even attempted to do it. Never occured to me in that car. I had employed trail braking plenty of times karting, but my foot never even twitched towards depressing the brake pedal mid-corner in the 911.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing that had me accepting that the problem is between the steering wheel and the seats was the difference in body control and mid-corner composure once I started making a concerted effort to be a smooth as possible. By this point it had been a few weeks since I had the opportunity to do a little spirited driving, and working off the rust was nice. Trail braking helped with smoothness, allowing the body of the vehicle to rotate around the center point rather than shoveling in extra lock on the steering wheel. This allowed me to keep my inputs positively tiny, turning the wheel no more than a couple degrees for everything but the tightest hairpin. The effect of this new-found smoothness was especially apparent in the 124 Spider due to the very soft suspension setup. The two roadsters absolutely came alive! They were darting in and out of corners with the greatest of ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I finally got these two techniques dialed in, I feel like I started to get a good look at what these cars were all about, and I must say I was very impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nd-mx-5-miata-sport&quot;&gt;ND MX-5 Miata Sport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/miata_front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ND Miata Sport&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with the ND interior, although sized for a flea in the height and shoulder width, proved to be more comfortable than a several forms of torture for a 6’4” driver like myself. I like to explain to people who ask that it’s a litte disconcerting when you have 5 contact points to your car: hands on the steering wheel (Hoperfully), feet on the pedals (Looking at you, Tesla autonomous drive!), butt in the seat (gravity can be a bitch), knees in the dash (a little concerning), and crown of the head about an inch into the cloth top (calling the chirporactor now). Three of those, great, that means the car you bought actually fits you as a human being, but when you get into the 5 spectrum, it feels like more of a coffin with a gas tank, but I digress. The pedals are simply sublime, being perfectly spaced for a heel toe (that I’m still working on, thanks Turo owner!). The shifter, and I say this with all honesty, is on par with the 911s and Boxsters that I’ve driven. To use vague and meaningless metaphor, the shifter feels connected and dialed in; there’s so little play and the engagement points and the shifter gates are so well spaced that you’ll never miss a shift. It’s such a special feeling getting ready for a shift with the engine at redline, feeling the knob buzz like a ride cymbal on rhythm with the rest of the band, and clicking it into gear. The clarity and harmony these inputs bring to the driver are simply sublime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that being said, I do have one gripe with the imputs: why in the absolute hell does the steering wheel not a telescope movement?! For that matter why does it only tilt from leg-guillotine height to knuckles-graze-your-knee height? There’s just not enough adjustability in the steering wheel to make it a comfortable car, tall people get this weird italian car driving position where your legs are all cramped upunder the dash and your arms are completely perpendicular to your shoulders. This is not a comfortable way to drive Mazda! Mazda corporate overlords, if you’re reading this, please please pleas… make a new RX-7! But also take a look at the steering wheel or whetever, but only if there’s time after the next rotary engine is developed with a durable apex seal. Look it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The revised suspension on the Sport trim was a real treat, it was firm but not harsh and gave enough body roll to be communicative at any speed. I have to say that while body roll helps the driver feel connected and in control, it can cause some nerves in your passengers! The grip was huge, which I think comes down to the tires and rear multi-link suspension that allows the body to roll without removing rubber from the pavement. This lateral grip in conjunction with the added rear diff that comes standard on the Sport trim kept the car planted on the road and rotating around an apex with unbelievable precision. Trail brake it into the apex and the car just seems to shrink around you (hard to imagine, I know!) the frontend bites and the whole body just squirrels around a corner, I’m not sure I’ve ever felt any other car quite as happy and willing to take a corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the engine, it was a total peach too. High revving with a great sound to it, I would consider it the real surprise of this car. When I heard that it was going to be a Skyactive engine at launch, I was a little worried that it would be totally gutless and just spin and spin with a wheeze and no torque. This couldn’t be further from the truth, I felt as though the torque of the enigne was fitting to the character of the car, there was a reasonable amount down low for traffic and the day-to-day, but up high in the rev range the torque was even and predictable. The soft fuel cut at redline meant you never had to shy away from the last thousand RPM’s the engine had to offer, which it where spirited driving should live!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan Kuhl</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Carbuying for Masochists</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/carbuying-for-masochists" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Carbuying for Masochists" /><published>2016-10-24T22:25:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T22:25:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/carbuying-for-masochists</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/carbuying-for-masochists">&lt;p&gt;Is car buying just too easy for you, too relaxing? Do you crave more excitement in your day-to-day? Want to raise the stakes and get that adrenaline coursing through your veins? Good news, I have just the thing for you: buy an exotic car like I did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where a normal person would think to themselves, “Hey, I need a used car, something flashy and fast, yeah. I’ll call a local dealership or go online to VehicleSwapper.com and find a suitable car within, say, 50 or so miles at a random used car lot that doesn’t look too sketchy. That’ll be fine!” And so off they go, not a care in the world. I, however, being a thoroughly &lt;del&gt;abnormal&lt;/del&gt; person enthusiast immediately thought, “screw the used lot, they only sell the leftovers and trash from auctions. I need me a mint condition sports car with all the records and the eternal admiration of the previous owner, yeah that’s what I need. I should find something on the Porsche forums, that’s where they hide the good shit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So began my deep descent into insanity and the phoenix-like resurrection into &lt;del&gt;debt&lt;/del&gt; car nirvana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after moving to Los Angeles and weaseling my way into a crew of canyon carvers and car nuts, I had to take a step forward from the trusty Mazda3 daily driver to something that could hang with the thoroughbreds. There were some constraints: price had to be reasonable, preferably at the bottom of its depreciation curve, a coupe, manual gearbox, and most importantly, it had to be tall guy approved. Nobody wants to drive with a greasy hair stain in the headliner above the driver’s seat, that’s just in poor taste. My wife insisted on something of quality. Much to my dismay that disqualifies Corvette, Viper, and the pony cars. I see out of Miatas and S2000s by looking over the windshield frame, so that simply won’t do. BMW drivers are, well, BMW drivers. I don’t know if I was ready to eschew blinkers from my driving habits and blast DJ Tiesto from the stereo on repeat. That left Porsche. It was small, nimble, focused on the driving experience. Sublime steering, the slickest six speed I’ve ever driven, and an engine in the wrong place. It was simply divine intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off to the races, I was tapped into Bring a Trailer, Rennlist, Pelican Parts, the PCA Classifieds, really anywhere that decent used Porsches frequented. One, two, three weeks went by and there was no bait worth biting. The cars were either too old, too high mileage, or god forbid a cabrio. Have you seen a pretty 911 cabrio? No? Me neither. After about two months of hunting I came across a post that was a week old already, it was a 2006 911 997.1 (many numbers, bare with me) Carrera S. I had all the qualifications, six speed, low mileage, all the options, and a great price. By great price I mean grossly over budget, naturally. One caveat, the car was half way across the country in a barren wasteland called Houston, TX. No big deal, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I send an email just to dip my toes in the water and the third party responsible for the sale of the car responds quickly. We’ll call him “The Mechanic”. Not for anonymity or any nefarious reasons, he was literally a mechanic, and an Australian, but that’s irrelevant. We schedule a call and I’m on my A game; I’m asking all the right questions, he knows I mean business. Oil leaks, regular oil changes, how long has it sat, has the water pump been replaced, IMS bearing, I just went down the list. He knew I meant business (at least I think so, in reality he probably didn’t care much either way). Before parting ways I asked for the DME (Digital Motor Electronics) report to be sent over at his earliest convenience. In Porsche land this report shows a log from the onboard diagnostics of how many revolutions the engine spent at any of six ranges of RPMs. This is a general gauge of how healthy the engine is and how well the car was cared form an absolute necessity when buying a Porsche. The DME showed up in my inbox the next morning and it was perfect. Things are getting more serious now! My next contact is with the owner, who shall be called The Owner, for dramatic effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of the car goes as follows: The first owner bought the car, put next to no miles on it, traded it in and bought a Ferrari. I like to think that being a Texan, he struck oil, a la There Will be Blood, exclaimed, “Fuck it, time for a Ferrari” and drove straight to Neiman Marcus to buy (calf) leather gloves and a (Burberry)scarf. Have to look the business, you know? Regardless of &lt;del&gt;my speculation&lt;/del&gt; the facts, the current owner got the car from a Porsche dealer as a Certified Pre-Owned vehicle with barely 25k miles in perfect condition. The Owner daily drove it 2 miles back and forth to work, tracked it a few times, and was absolutely in love with the car. The Owner is selling the car because she had to leave the country for work and was unable to import the car to Scotland. How hard could a vehicle transaction be even if they are out of the country? Is The Owner the most convincing Nigerian Scammer on Earth? I swear that thought went through my head. Never faltering, I looked potential disaster in the face and laughed. Some clever accounting with a sprinkle of numbers crunching and the car was just within budget. A pair of one-way tickets to Houston quickly followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a run-down of the plan: My wife and I are going to fly to Houston, get the car to a PPI, purchase it, stay the night with my brother, then embark on an epic road trip through west Texas (as fast as humanly possible), over to Santa Fe New Mexico, up to Flagstaff Arizona, and gracefully swooping back to home base in LA before both of us had to go back to work. Does this plan sound farfetched? I didn’t think so. Fun? Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I like to quote from books I haven’t read, “The best-laid plans of mice and men often go awry.” Here’s what actually happened. We fly from LAX to Houston on time and without incident, take an Uber right to The Mechanic, luggage in tow. He shows us the car and it’s even better than the pictures! The car is absolutely immaculate. He drove it first because I wouldn’t do the irresponsible stuff on a test drive and rightfully scared the shit out of my wife and myself. I get the keys and head off to Swiss Garage (shout out, those guys are great!) to get my Pre Purchase Inspection done. Swiss garage is two miles away. I had two police cars tail me on the way there. Then two more on the way back just to keep me on edge. I’m pretty sure the Texas registration was expired too, lucky I didn’t get pulled over or I would have had to do some real smooth talking. You’ll never feel more conspicuous than when you’re driving a small sports car through a bad neighborhood in the truck infested streets of Texas. Yee-Haw!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learn on my test drive that the car has a factory short-throw shifter kit that nobody cared to mention. Schwing! Long story short, the PPI went flawlessly save a rear headlight leveling sensor that was Macgyver-ed back into working order with some duct tape. The Mechanic was quite proud of that nugget of handy work upon mention of it, prevented(ing) the sensor from having to be replaced. Good enough for me. By now I’m all stages go, let’s do this thing. I ask to get in touch with The Owner to work out a (lower) number and finalize financing. This is where the plan goes a little off the rails. The Mechanic informs me that the only way he gets in touch with the owner is sending her a Facebook message and waiting for her to call on Skype. “Well that’s a little haphazard” I’m &lt;del&gt;pessimistically&lt;/del&gt; optimistically thinking to myself. He assures me that this is the only way to get in contact with her. Maybe she is a Nigerian scammer, this is a pretty elaborate means of communication after all. The hours are ticking by on this Friday afternoon while I wait for a call from the bank and The Owner. Neither come. I was stuck in Texas with no money until Monday evening at the earliest, no communication with The Owner, and not enough time to make it back to LA if I wait it out. I believe they call this being between a rock and a hard place. We decide to cut our losses and hop the first flight out of there to try and salvage any part of our vacation time from work. The first flight out just happens to be straight to Las Vegas. Nice. Thanks to a combination of my wife’s mysterious gipsy powers and lack of patience we got out of Houston the day before flooding, that would have stranded us there for days, rolled through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a week and I finally get in contact with The Owner; She was vacationing in rural Australia with her family and was unable to find anywhere with WiFi to give me a call except the local McDonalds. That makes communication difficult to say the least. I say I want to buy the car then careen delicately into negotiations. I ask for money off, she is insistent on the asking price, hardball ensues and I put my foot down at $500 under asking price. Take it or leave it. How could $500 possible(ly) be worth risking the sale to her, who the hell else was going to jump through this many hoops to get this car at any price?! The conversation bitterly ends and she says she’ll get back to me. Radio silence for the next 24 hours. I get the email from The Owner saying they’re going to accept the offer! I thought it was all downhill from here, I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my sweet road trip was now out of the question, I got a shipping truck lined up and asked that the title be sent separately from the car by way of UPS overnight. I get the cashier’s check for the car, handcuff it to my arm like an action movie, and head over to the local chase bank two blocks away. I deposit the check in The Owner’s account in a worryingly easy transaction with the teller. I’m not a religious man, but a little hail mary would have been the proper thing to do in the moment. Shortly thereafter the check clears, the car gets swooped up into the carrier,  and the pre-signed title is getting shipped out to me. I’m in the clear right? Thankfully, The Mechanic completely disregarded my repeated request to use UPS and sends it out certified mail through the ever reliable local USPS branch that has literally one star on Yelp. That’s who should be trusted with my damn title! I’m still &lt;del&gt;very&lt;/del&gt; a little bitter about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One week goes by and the shipping information has not updated past the branch it was dropped off at, the person at the post office call center assures me that this is fairly normal. “Sometimes it just gets scanned as normal mail and not tracked mail, there’s nothing to be concerned about” she says. Fine. Patience is paramount. By this time the car had been delivered already and was sitting in the garage awaiting paperwork. Two weeks, then three crawl by and I start to panic. Endless calls to the USPS call centers, distribution centers, and branches come up fruitless. All the while my beast sits caged and undriven. Fate is a cruel mistress, maybe this is karmic retribution for past transgressions? Why me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ordering a replacement title is not as easy of a proposition as it sounds, I would have to send a request for a replacement title with payment from California to the Texas DMV, have them send the replacement to Scotland to get signed and such by The Owner, have her send it back to California so I can go to the DMV and register the car. By this time The Owner was becoming irritated and unresponsive making this simply not an option. There had to be a simpler way. Sure enough, I stumbled upon the thought of cars in estate sales and how there had to be a means of transferring rights of the cars after the owner was driving the streets of heaven. Eureka! There’s a power of attorney form that Texas has hidden in a sub page of a sub page of the DMV website. A clerk I talked with from the DMV confirmed that this rather unconventional means of title transferral could indeed be used in my situation. I signed and scanned the forms, emailed them to The Owner that same day asking her to sign two copies and mail them to me. A week or so later the letter was in my mailbox and no later was it forwarded with a replacement title request and a (yes this is true) $3 check for the Texas DMV. For those keeping tabs, this is now a month into dream car ownership with zero miles driven. Zero. Miles. Not one week later the golden ticket shows up in my mailbox and there was just two hurdles in my way now, the line at the DMV and the pain of giving them a couple grand in registration and sales tax. That one really hurt. Thankfully those two were quick and I finally had the joy of letting my prized stallion stretch it’s legs in the Malibu canyons. I had reached the holy land, hallowed ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To review for the sake of posterity, when purchasing a car make sure to meet the following criteria: set up a private sale with an unreachable international seller, whom requires voodoo magic to contact. Be confident with the robust and reliable process of purchasing a vehicle by buying one-way plane ticket to a place far far away, and always be sure to ship irreplaceable documents through USPS. That part’s really important. What doesn’t kill you makes you stronger, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan Kuhl</name></author><summary type="html">Is car buying just too easy for you, too relaxing? Do you crave more excitement in your day-to-day? Want to raise the stakes and get that adrenaline coursing through your veins? Good news, I have just the thing for you: buy an exotic car like I did!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t Daily Your Track Car</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/dont-daily-your-track-car" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't Daily Your Track Car" /><published>2016-10-24T22:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T22:20:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/dont-daily-your-track-car</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/dont-daily-your-track-car">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part I: The Hunt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you a piece of advice: do not buy a questionably legal, 15-year-old track car that you intend to daily drive. It may seem like a good idea, that you’ll make it work, and that it will be fun. It’s not, you won’t and it isn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My story starts in the summer of 2014. I was an auto-obsessed 23 year-old living in not so car friendly Boston. I was ready to leave Boston and began applying for various jobs in Seattle and Los Angeles. My older brother – and little devil in my ear – was living in LA and convinced me to make the move. I appreciated his desire to get me to LA, but should have used common sense to ignore his next proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I had a place to live I was scouring forums, Craigslist, and Autotrader for cars. What the hell was I going buy? Porsche 996? BMW 2002? Buick Grand National?! A couple weeks before I was scheduled to move I got a text from my brother: “Let’s buy a track car. You can daily it, and we’ll split everything.” In theory this made sense, my commute was ~4 miles, I wanted to go to the track as much possible, and I wanted to buy a fun car I could take to the canyons. In reality this was a hugely irresponsible decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up in the suburbs of Seattle. My dad and brother are also total car-nuts. Not in the “let’s go restore an old Saab in the garage” way, but in the “let’s go to the Porsche dealership and subscribe to every car magazine imaginable” way. What’s my point? Well, I’m not the MOST mechanically inclined. I can change a tire, swap rotors and pads, put in a headlight, change fluids, etc. But ask me to tune a carburetor and I’ll point you to the nearest mechanic. I regret not taking shop classes growing up, or working for a mechanic in high school. One day when I have the time and money I’ll build a project car. That story will probably start the same way this one does. But I’m a moron and morons make the same mistake over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a naïve 23-year-old and agreed to the track car idea. Now it was a matter figuring out what to buy. As always, Miata seemed to be the answer. Cheap, reliable, fast and fun. The only problem was that my brother did not fit, and was not going to fit without substantial fabrication of the driver’s seat and rails. In attempt to avoid this, we moved on from Miata’s. I then stumbled upon a fully built E30 with an S52. The car was beautiful. Brand new paint, a low mileage motor, and zero track time. The owner had built it, but decided to sell it in favor of his 1000 hp GT-R. Can’t blame him for that… I drove it around Van Nuys and was blown away. It was screaming fast, but more importantly, incredibly balanced. Before pulling the trigger I took a step back and decided to pass. As clean as the car was – it had no interior at all, a full cage, no A/C, no stereo, and no passenger seat. I’m not THAT dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten days before I made my move to LA we stumbled upon the winning car. An Alpine white 1999 BMW M3. The owner had purchased the car with the intention of building an NASA race-car. Poly bushings everywhere, a cage, and about $3,000 worth of suspension work. The owner had simply lost interest in the project. The car had racing seats with 6-point harnesses, but maintained A/C, a stereo, and most of an interior. For $11,000, it was on the high end of the market for an E36, but I figured I’d spend a lot more getting it to that point. Note to self: never spend more on a car because it has mods. Day 1 stuff here, but when you let your emotions get the best of you buying a car, you’re screwed. I was done for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same weekend I moved to LA, my brother picked up and drove our new M3 to LA from San Francisco. The next day I met up with friends and spent all morning in the Malibu Canyons. The car was great. Everything about the car was great. Or so my tiny peanut brain thought. It took all of one commute to ask myself: “What the hell have I done.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part II: So Far, So Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My M3 was not yet registered as I pulled out of the short term housing I was living in and headed down the street to work. I severely underestimated how stiff the combination of race springs, a cage, and poly bushings would be. The stiff ride didn’t bother me driving up the 1 to Malibu, or ripping around canyons at speed on nice roads with no traffic. Sitting in stop and go traffic during rush hour was another story. It felt like I was driving around the Flintstones mobile. Oh well. I knew I could power through. Hell, the car was fun to drive and fast – I didn’t need a comfortable commute – and driving a terrible daily driver is a rite of passage for car-guys (idiots).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first track day experience in the M3 was about a month into my ownership. I hauled my brother, a set of Hankook R-S3 tires mounted to Kosei K1s and a box of tools to Buttonwillow for a Speed Ventures HPDE event. The day went off without a hitch. We did a combined 10 sessions on track with the car without issue. On my last session I overcorrected coming out of the Bus Stop and spun. Turns out spinning on R-compounds = flat spotting tires. The right rear tire was done for. Fortunately, it was the end of the day, and we simply packed up, mounted the street tires, and called it a day. The car couldn’t have run better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a track car the M3 was everything I could have imagined and more. The car was so predictable – perfect for someone who was learning. Fast enough to have fun, but slow enough that I wasn’t afraid of driving at close to 10/10ths. As a road car, it sucked. It was loud, harsh, low, and attracted all the wrong sorts of attention. Just a few weeks into ownership I took my girlfriend to dinner for her birthday. After putting on a nice dress for dinner, we got in the car and she buckled the 6-point harness between her legs. “Eric” she said, “it’s time for a new car. This is insane.” At the time I laughed it off. With 20/20 hindsight I would have tried to sell the car right then and there. It would have saved me a lot of money. But like I’ve mentioned, I have a peanut brain, so the M3 experiment continued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part III: Things That Go Boom Part 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t long before our first major mishap. Halfway through an HPDE at Streets of Willow, the car began sputtering and dying. It would start, but wouldn’t idle, and was way down on power. Because I’m not mechanically inclined, AAA was called, and the car was towed to the mechanic. That night I had also made plans with my girlfriends. Instead of being home by 6, I was riding bitch in a tow truck hoping the car was only a little bit broken. Neither one of us was thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no clue what to expect, but the news was not good. An over-rev lead to a bent valve: a top end rebuild was in order. Many thousands of dollars of labor later the top end rebuild was complete. We also replaced the power steering pump, shifter bushings, and made a few other minor fixes. I was certainly frustrated, but blamed myself for the over-rev. Had I known the car was cursed, I wouldn’t have bothered with the rebuild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the rebuild I was hitching rides to work with my brother, friends and Uber. The car was out of commission for about three weeks, during which time I had plenty of time to question my own sanity. Did it make any sense to daily drive this M3? No. Should I wait to have a track car until I have a spare garage and more disposable income? Yes. Should I sell the M3 and cut my losses? Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead I had an even better idea. Time for the M3 to have a stablemate. I didn’t have much cash, nor did I have a garage. I wanted something that we could use to tow, I could take up to Mammoth in the winter, and most importantly, wouldn’t cost an arm and a leg to own. 1995 Buick Roadmaster Estate it was. I got the car inspected, and four days later was in Fresno picking up the most American car I’ll ever own. For $5,000 I was the proud owner of an extremely clean Roadmaster Estate with 120k original miles, a 5.7-liter LT-1, a 5,000-pound towing capacity, and room for 8. It was everything the M3 was not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things were looking up. I had a couch on wheels to get me to and from work, my girlfriend no longer had to strap a harness every time we went anywhere, and the famously treacherous LA roads were no longer an obstacle course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part IV: Things That Go Boom Part 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there was a single aha moment for me as it relates to racing cars, it happened at an a HPDE event at Spring Mountain Motorsports Ranch in Parumph, NV. The private track opened its doors for the event. I would be hard pressed to find any redeemable qualities in the town most famously known for legalizing prostitution. The track however, was something special. Brand new asphalt, long high speed sweepers, decreasing radius turns, and long straights. The track had everything, and most importantly, the place was dead. No traffic jams and no S2000 drivers who refused to let slower cars pass. We had two perfect days of driving that weekend. Sunday afternoon we loaded the M3 onto to rented U-Haul trailer, and towed the 300 miles’ home without incident. If there was a high point during M3 ownership, this was it. Unfortunately, my ownership low point was just weeks away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Spring Mountain, I was blessed with about a month and half of pain free driving before the car gods took a steaming dump all over me. My brother and I attended a track event at Streets of Willow. It was a hot day, but nothing out of the ordinary for the desert. In my brothers third session of the day he entered the pits early because he heard a loud slapping noise coming from under the hood. We popped the hood and noticed that one of the fan blades was partially torn. We ripped off the damaged blade, but the uneven fan would whip the shroud as it spun.  We called our mechanic, and he suggested cutting off all of the fan blades one by one. As long as weren’t sitting in traffic on the 405 in 100-degree heat, the car wouldn’t overheat. All was well. We thought. We performed plastic surgery on the fan, filled up the coolant tank, loaded up the car, and headed back towards to LA. My brother was driving the M3, and I was following in the Buick. It was but 30 miles before a giant cloud of black smoke consumed the road in front of me. Disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the fan broke it punctured a small hole in the coolant tank. The puncture was small enough that there was no noticeable leak at the track. It slowly emptied as we drove home, and within a few minutes, boom. To this day I am not sure how we did not notice the leak, or how my brother didn’t notice the temp gauge spike. In any event, what was done, was done. We had caused serious damage to the head gasket and scored multiple pistons. The only logical fix was a new motor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part V: What’s Done Is Done&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chalk it up to inexperience. Chalk it up to stupidity. The reality was that I was now out another $3,000. The car was worth its weight scrap with a blown motor, and a new motor was still cheaper than a Miata. With that in mind, we moved forward with the swap. Our mechanic found a low mileage S52, and over the course of a few weeks the new motor was dropped in, along with headers and full exhaust. If we were going to spend money the car, we were going to make sure the thing sounded damn good. We also added auxiliary water temp gauge, oil temp gauge, and most importantly a mechanical fan. No more overheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason I thought this was going to be the end of our struggle fest. The day we got the car back, I drove down the street to get takeout. On the way back, the car suddenly died. I assumed dead battery, but the car was running and shutoff waiting at a light. My brother and I pushed the car about half a mile back to our house, and tried to jump the car. No dice. AAA was in front of the house the next morning. The fix was a simple fuse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part V: Now What?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I knew without a doubt the car was cursed. I certainly did some dumb stuff along the way, but the eight or so track days we had attended had cost us something obscene, like $1,000 per session. It was outrageous. I still wanted to go to the track. I still wanted to drive in the canyons. I still wanted to own an E36 M3. I was just afraid of driving the damn thing. The car was my personal Eleanor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months ago the car went into the garage. It gets pulled out for the occasional drive. But I am still petrified of track days. It makes no sense to sell the car, but at some point I need to simply cut my losses and accept the fact that I experienced a true money pit, and paid for great stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would I recommend buying a track car as your commuter? Of course not. Would I do this all again? No question. My experiences with the M3 have been mostly terrible, but I’d never learn about what not to do, had I not done them. It’s like the silly cliché thing they tell you in 4th grade: you learn more from your mistakes than your successes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note – anyone want to buy a highly modified 1999 BMW M3?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Eric Wahl</name></author><summary type="html">Part I: The Hunt</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Analog Drives Manifesto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/analog-drives-manifesto" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analog Drives Manifesto" /><published>2016-10-24T22:13:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T22:13:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/analog-drives-manifesto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2016/10/24/analog-drives-manifesto">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are car enthusiasts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We care about the experience: the car, the driver, and most importantly, the stories. Analog Drives is a celebration of car culture, car enthusiasts, and shared experiences in the community and on the road. We believe people and their stories trump lap times and lateral G’s. We intend to create content that fulfills that mindset. We will present meaningful commentary and interviews on cars from all walks of life, so long as the owners are passionate and the cars are driven. We create works that you will become engrossed in and that will inspire you to seek out similar experiences. But above all we want to help expose the people and stories that make the car community so special. We are Analog Drives.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Analog Drives Team</name></author><summary type="html">We are car enthusiasts. We care about the experience: the car, the driver, and most importantly, the stories. Analog Drives is a celebration of car culture, car enthusiasts, and shared experiences in the community and on the road. We believe people and their stories trump lap times and lateral G’s. We intend to create content that fulfills that mindset. We will present meaningful commentary and interviews on cars from all walks of life, so long as the owners are passionate and the cars are driven. We create works that you will become engrossed in and that will inspire you to seek out similar experiences. But above all we want to help expose the people and stories that make the car community so special. We are Analog Drives.</summary></entry></feed>