<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-04T14:54:27+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/</id><title type="html">Five Weeks Abroad</title><subtitle>Life in a new place... for a little while</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The One About How We Smuggled Penny into Spain</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/23/the-one-about-how-we-smuggled-penny-into-spain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One About How We Smuggled Penny into Spain" /><published>2017-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/23/the-one-about-how-we-smuggled-penny-into-spain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/23/the-one-about-how-we-smuggled-penny-into-spain">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or How We Learned to Stop Worrying and Trust the Stamp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were in Paris earlier this year we met an amazing couple, Chelsea and Trey Stone &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oursteppinstones.com/&quot;&gt;Our Steppin Stones Blog&lt;/a&gt;. They were two expats in their 30s that decided to move to Spain and fulfil their dream of living abroad for a year, bringing along their Pekinese Cashman. Meeting them felt like a sign, giving us the inspiration for our current trip. Before meeting Chelsea and Trey, we had no idea that you could even bring a pet into Europe from the US. It’s not something that we really ever sat and talked about until after we had met them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Cashman.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cashman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing that it was actually possible made it that much more attractive to travel with Penny. If you already know me, you know how much I love this furry little beast and leaving her behind to travel anywhere is heart wrenching. So when Ryan proposed the idea of us traveling to Spain for five weeks, my one stipulation was that we bring Penny with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Penny_Lounge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny Loungin and the Airport Lounge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this post to explain our first hand experience and what research was needed to complete the process. Upon doing our own research for Penny, we put together what we thought we needed from various Pet-Travel websites, the CDC, and USDA websites. However, we never found anyone’s own experience going through this process detailed and validating if what we thought we needed was correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, our process of &lt;del&gt;smuggling&lt;/del&gt; completely legally getting Penny into the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Penny_Peetime.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny's First Pee in Spain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you Google “getting dog into Spain from US” the first result is a link to PetTravel.com&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pettravel.com/immigration/spain.cfm&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, a company that assists in the relocation of pets internationally. They were our best reference throughout this process since they detail exactly what is and what is not needed for travel into Spain (as well as other countries).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: Thanks to the Stones, we knew that Spain’s requirements were basically the simplest for importing a dog into the EU. Going through Spain, France or Germany will allow you get your pet in, and once in, a pet passport will allow uncomplicated travel throughout the EU. If you were going into the UK, for instance, the process is far more complicated and if you don’t have the proper paperwork, could result in a required quarantine period for your pet upon arrival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to PetTravel.com we knew that the first thing Penny needed was the correct microchip. Luckily, she was already microchipped and her vet confirmed that the right one was in. The next thing was for her to have a current rabies vaccine. Penny had been vaccinated last June 2016 with a 3-yr vaccine and Spain recognizes 3 yr rabies vaccines, so we were good on that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process for Spain does require that the pet receive the rabies vaccine AFTER being microchipped with “an ISO 11784/11785 compliant 15 digit pet microchip” (1). We didn’t have a problem with this part but if Penny had not had the proper chip in already, she would have had to get the right one placed, be re-vaccinated, and have to wait 21 days before traveling. So this process has be started with at least two to three months notice if there’s already a set travel date, just to have a comfortable window of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the US is recognized as a rabies-controlled country, Penny did not require a Rabies Titer Test. The next step was getting her health certificate. According to PetTravel.com, because we were traveling from the US, “the veterinarian must be accredited by the USDA and the health certificate must be endorsed by the State USDA office.” We simply called up our vet to check this, and the USDA website has some helpful info on this too&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/pet-travel/find-a-vet/pet-travel-locate-an-accredited-vet&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another side note, we believe that PetTravel.com makes it’s business off selling these forms in their blank state to users as a service. These forms are available for free on the USDA website&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/pet-travel/by-country/eu/pettravel-spain&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and any vet that you visit to get the form completed will have the form available as well. No need to pay for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Penny_Health_Cert.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny's Health Certificate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The health certificate needed to be completed and endorsed by the USDA within 10 days of our arrival date. This is an important distinction if your flight spans two days due to timezones. We made an appointment with our vet to fit that timeline. Our travel date was set for September 6th with arrival on September 7th, so we had to keep in mind that the USDA office would be closed for Labor Day, September 4th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked up the nearest state office for the USDA Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) through their website&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aphis.usda.gov/aphis/pet-travel/service-centers-endorsement-offices&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and crossed our fingers that it wasn’t in Sacramento. There is one located in El Segundo directly south of LAX. We were in luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had called the USDA APHIS state office to see if we could make an appointment to endorse our paperwork. Due to the amazing efficiency and dedication of government agencies, they were open Monday-Friday from 7:30am-11am. Hope you have a sick-day handy for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan took Penny to the vet to get the health certificate completed the Thursday before our trip. That next day, I showed up at the APHIS office at 7am and met six other people in line. Living in LA means getting everything done before the birds are up and traffic gets going, if you really mean business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in line, I got to talk to some of the other folks going through the same process. There was a young Irish gal that suddenly had her work visa revoked and was stuck figuring out how to get herself and her dog back to Ireland within a week (thanks Trump). Remember I noted that the UK is hard to get your pet into, well Ireland apparently is worse. (No, Ireland is not part of the UK, just Northern Ireland).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after 2-3 hours and about $30 later I had Penny’s health certificate stamped by an official at the USDA APHIS office and she was set to fly! I gotta say, the lady getting everyone’s paperwork in order was super nice. Overall a refreshing experience for a government office. I really mean this, for once I’m not being sarcastic here. She was really, really nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another potential pitfall in this whole endeavor was the flight. We booked a direct flight to Spain to avoid having to get Penny’s paperwork for several countries. The only direct flights from LAX to anywhere in Spain were with Iberia and Norwegian airlines. We ended up taking Norwegian Airlines for the less expensive fare. A direct flight is a must when traveling with a pet as the rules get strange and expensive with multiple hops in other countries. US law dictates that a flight starting or terminating in the US must comply with the service animal requirements mandated by the FAA, meaning that the airline has to accept service animals (including ESA) on the flight regardless of company policy. Keep in mind that ESA certificates are only valid for one year within receiving it, and the airlines will check this date. We’ll come back to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thoroughly reading through the Norwegian Airlines pet policy&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.norwegian.com/en/travel-info/baggage/travelling-with-pets/&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, we determined that Penny should be good-to-go for a fee that we normally pay to the airline to carry her onboard with us. After booking the flight we called Norwegian to reserve a seat for her and determine what the fee would be. They kindly informed us that they do not transport pets internationally between the US and Europe. We asked that they cancel our booking and we would look for another flight, which they told us was impossible as we hadn’t purchased the more expensive tickets that one could cancel. This is where Penny’s valid ESA certificate comes into the mix, because of that and the direct flight we were able to bring her in the cabin despite Norwegian’s corporate policy of not transporting pets internationally. In addition Norwegian is not allowed to charge a fee for a service animal’s travels under FAA policy, so that was a plus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Penny_Airplane.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny inside plane&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so this post has gone on for far longer than I had intended. So I will end with our experience getting into Spain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a sweaty 11 hour flight, we got off the plane, showed our passports at Border Patrol, picked up our bags and made our way to Customs (en español: Aduana). This is where they quickly reviewed our health certificate and scanned Penny’s microchip. So yes, they DO check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we were officially and legally IN SPAIN WITH PENNY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I want to thank the academy, and my parents for their continued support through this process. But most importantly, I want to thank the lady at APHIS, whose wonderful enthusiasm for her work gave me the motivation to not give up even when I thought we would all get stopped at customs in Spain. Thank you all!!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Penny_Train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pennys in Trains&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that’s seriously how I felt. Like Jennifer Lawrence at the Oscars. Except without all the tripping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this went on forever, I will detail how we got Penny a cute Pet Passport here in Malaga and how we are getting her back to the US, in a future post. No worries, it’s a much simpler process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09232017/Penny_Pet_Passport.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pet Passport&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this was a helpful and informative post for those curious on how to import your pet to the EU. It should not be used as an official reference source, but the handy dandy websites included, should be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales, Ryan Kuhl</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="dog" /><category term="international" /><category term="health" /><category term="certificate" /><category term="USDA" /><category term="APHIS" /><summary type="html">Or How We Learned to Stop Worrying and Trust the Stamp</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where We go to Seville</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/20/the-one-where-we-go-to-seville" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We go to Seville" /><published>2017-09-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/20/the-one-where-we-go-to-seville</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/20/the-one-where-we-go-to-seville">&lt;p&gt;We’re now in Malaga and settling into that laid back Malagueño style of life. Our weekend in Seville went as quick as it came and we wish we had more time there. It’s a beautiful city. We were so lucky to have found it during a cold front where it wasn’t in the 100s the entire time (or ever) while we were there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we rented bikes and decided to tour the city with only Google Maps and our guide book on Andalucia. This turned out to be a very good idea if you know how to navigate the maze of medieval European streets. But anything is possible with Google Maps, right? More on this later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We biked our way into El Centro de Seville to check out the bullring, La Plaza de Toros de la Maestranza. Neither of us are exactly fans of this gruesome sport but much of Spanish culture and history is embedded into bullfighting, so we figured a tour of the ring couldn’t hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Ryan_El_Torro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan El Toro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside, the tour guide led us around to different exhibition rooms that detailed the art and history of bullfighting. Also on display were the heads of the bulls defeated by famous bullfighters, trapping them forever in the place they were killed for sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Torro_Exhibit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toro Exhibit Room&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then led into the arena where they released one of those bulls and we all ran around for our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/El_Torro_Sara.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sara El Torro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just kidding. But if that was part of the tour, I know people would still pay to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Torro_Wall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan Torro Wall&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the bullring was neat to see but we both agreed we wouldn’t want to watch one live. We’re not Hemingway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/El_Torro_Selfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toro Plaza Selfie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had read about the oldest bar in Sevilla in our guidebook, so we biked there next. We would return here at night but I felt I had to get a picture of the front if it in daylight.
Take a look at the year the bar was founded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Rinconcillo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;El Rinconcillo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1670! This bar in Seville is older than America! So yeah, that blew my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From El Rinconcillo we biked east towards an Indian restaurant to get some lunch. We feasted. There are no pictures of this because we were elbow deep into some Tikka Masala and garlic naan.
After lunch is where we found out we were not yet experts in navigating medieval European streets. Let me present you with Exhibit A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Screenshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my defense, I had been following Ryan for a while before I asked to see the map. We had a pretty good laugh about it at the outskirts of town. Still makes me chuckle. That’s got to be the best picture I’ve taken on this trip so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way back (thanks to my amazing powers of orientation) to the Airbnb and reunited with Penny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Stormtroopers_Penny.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny with Storm Troopers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you that follow @kuhladventures on Instagram you’ve already seen a similar picture and know that Ryan is the nerdiest person I know (and love very much). To explain why there were Storm Troopers here in the first place, we think there was a board game block party happening in the background. Nerds are everywhere and anywhere, even in the ex-red light district of Seville where we happened to be staying (unbeknownst to us before we booked).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we made it out to “The Mushrooms” as we liked to call them. Right in the middle of Seville is a massive wooden structure that looks very similar to huge mushrooms. It’s actually called the Metropol Parasol and was designed by German architect Jürgen Mayer. The view from the walkway on the mushrooms is lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Mushrooms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mushrooms&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended the night back at El Rinconcillo with some Rioja y jamon Iberico. The oldest bar in Sevilla also has the oldest bartenders inside of it. Despite their age, they were quick at taking down orders from the dozens of patrons visiting the famous establishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09202017/Rinconcillo_Inside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Inside El Rinconcillo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If those hams hanging from the ceiling look sweaty, it’s because they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a wonderful time in Seville. If you find yourself in Spain, I highly recommend a visit. Be prepared for some heat, beautiful architecture, and confusing streets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="tapas" /><category term="toro" /><category term="seville" /><summary type="html">We’re now in Malaga and settling into that laid back Malagueño style of life. Our weekend in Seville went as quick as it came and we wish we had more time there. It’s a beautiful city. We were so lucky to have found it during a cold front where it wasn’t in the 100s the entire time (or ever) while we were there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where Ryan Finally Writes an Article</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/17/the-one-where-ryan-finally-writes-an-article" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where Ryan Finally Writes an Article" /><published>2017-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/17/the-one-where-ryan-finally-writes-an-article</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/17/the-one-where-ryan-finally-writes-an-article">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09172017/map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Malaga Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bit of a change, I wanted to talk for a bit about the process of working abroad and getting to a place where this
was possible. I think a lot of software developers and engineers talk a lot about being a ‘digital nomad’, or a person
who can maintain a consistent income anywhere in the world. I usually see this being said in conjunction with mention of
Tim Ferris, freelance working, and a tinge of arrogance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for something a little different, I wanted to do the digital nomad life with a more traditional 9-to-5 type job.
I think in the long run working at a larger tech company has better long term viability. I’m still learning core skills
and valuable insight from working with far more experiences devs that I wouldn’t be able to get if I was head honcho,
it’s the little fish in a big pond strategy. While less flexible than being a freelancer, the tech giants like Google,
Facebook and WordPress have brought an expectation of remote work for the tech workforce, and this should be taken
advantage of to the fullest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Farris had some interesting insight into this in ‘The 4-Hour Work Week’ where he pushes the reader to work remotely
more often and to engage in deep work while simultaneously reducing the total hours of work per week. I can see the
logic behind this for sure, but it take a lot of dicipline to actually employ. I’ve been slowly adding more remote
working days to my regular work schedule to test my own dicipline with this newfound freedom while still close to the
office; working from the couch or quiet coffee shops. This was integral to becoming better at working remote, 0 to 100
is a strategy that is setting you up for failure. Another lucky coincidence is that my job has offices in several
timezones. This puts a need for people to communicate asynchronously through slack (hopefully) or email (if they’re mad
at you I guess). This culture of employees working between offices and timezones was promising for a more extreme
arrangement or working overseas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big part of the pitch was in setting up strict guidelines of availability and response time in case of
an incident or outage. Fall back plans if my laptop were to break and a contingency plan was if things didn’t work
out. With all this outlined it seemed to be pretty low risk, if the laptop gets stolen by gypsies, buy a new one and
expense it. Be available half the day on west-coast time, be no more than two hours away from your computer in case of
an emergency. Done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months of working remote a day or two a week went well, contingency plan was made, nothing left but the big pitch, I want to
work from Europe for 5 weeks! My manager vouched for me and asked up the chain of command. Everybody seemed a little dubious but
okay with the transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09172017/wifi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My WiFi Lifeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the trip it was very important to get all my tasks in order, &lt;em&gt;mise en place&lt;/em&gt; as the French say.
I was assigned two large projects and made a point to get all the relevant information I could think of, reviewed and
re-reviewed the tickets so I wouldn’t be held up with missing informaition forcing me to make meetings or shape my
schedule too much around Pacific Time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09172017/elevator.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;404 Elevator Not Found&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it’s off-we-go to Spain for 5 weeks! I’m a little over a week in as of now and I think it seems to be going well.
I’ve been getting what I think to be more work done and have managed to stay more relaxed and focused in the new
surroundings than I had anticipated. With a solid 3 hour pre-breakfast stint and another 3 or so hours after dinner I
have managed to keep my workload on par with being in the office, so I guess Tim Ferris might be onto something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll see how the remainder of the trip goes! :es:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09172017/malaga.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Malaga&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for a write up of how we got Penny (our pug) to be able to join us overseas for our trip! Spoiler alert it
rhymes with paperwork and the Benjamins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09172017/penny_chin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny on the Train&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ryan Kuhl</name></author><category term="digital-nomad" /><category term="advice" /><category term="software-development" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where We Go To Dorne</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/16/the-one-where-we-go-to-dorne" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We Go To Dorne" /><published>2017-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/16/the-one-where-we-go-to-dorne</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/16/the-one-where-we-go-to-dorne">&lt;p&gt;Yes, DORNE. The Alcázar in Seville is where Game of Thrones filmed scenes for the Water Gardens of Dorne for Season 5. We’re pretty big GoT fans (who isn’t?) and once I learned about this nearby filming location, we had to get our butts to Seville.
So we did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning we hopped a train from Malaga and made it to Seville in just over 2 hours. Penny enjoyed her first train ride ever, and it was well documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/PennyTrain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny at the train station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Andalucia produces around 20% of the world’s olive oil? This region has olive trees for days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/Olives.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Olive Trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we arrived at our destination, we set out for the Alcázar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a monument of Miguel de Cervantes and had to stop for a quick photo op. My mom always spoke of her school days and how much she dreaded reading Don Quixote, equating it to Shakespeare in Spanish. It’s on my reading list..for some distant future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/Cervantes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cervantes Bust&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Alcázar of Seville is a medieval Islamic palace. If I had to explain the Alcázar in one word, it would be magnificent. The architecture is eye candy and you could easily spend an entire day in the gardens. I mean, just look at this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarArch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alcazar Arch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarCourt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alcazar Courtyard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarSpout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alcazar Waterspout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can see the orange building where Prince Doran of House Martell would sit and overlook the Water Gardens from.
No wonder the Game of Thrones team decided to film here. The show managed to find a gorgeous location to shoot, and its equally beautiful on screen and in real life. I didn’t want to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarSara.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alcazar Sara in gardens&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I mentioned my love of maps? Ancient maps are the best. There was this impressive twenty-foot tapestry of ancient Europe inside the Alcázar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarSaraMap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sara in front of map tapestry&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It shows Spain facing Africa as well as Sicily. Here it is again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarMap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Huge map no. 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, Seville is wonderful. Even the weather is great. We got here during a “cold front.” It has been in the mid 80s all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be in Seville for the weekend, so more updates on this awesome city coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09162017/AlcazarRyanArch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan looking at arches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="game-of-thones" /><category term="dorne" /><category term="seville" /><category term="alcazar" /><summary type="html">Yes, DORNE. The Alcázar in Seville is where Game of Thrones filmed scenes for the Water Gardens of Dorne for Season 5. We’re pretty big GoT fans (who isn’t?) and once I learned about this nearby filming location, we had to get our butts to Seville. So we did!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where Sara Gets Sick</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/13/the-one-where-sara-gets-sick" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where Sara Gets Sick" /><published>2017-09-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/13/the-one-where-sara-gets-sick</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/13/the-one-where-sara-gets-sick">&lt;p&gt;I apologize for the use of the third person in that title, I know I’m not Elmo. I’m keeping this one short because not much happened over the past two days due to a nasty cold I acquired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, we tried out the tapas bar down the street from the apartment. I’ve got to say, despite feeling crummy, there’s nothing like midday sangria. As true tourists, we have to try all that Andalucia has to offer. Honestly, I’m pretty convinced there’s no alcohol in any of the sangria they sell here. It all tastes like fruity Sprite to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09132017/sangria.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan pointing to jar of Sangria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I finally got to try REAL Manchego cheese, made in Spain, while in Spain. Redemption cheese for the win!! It was alright. It was missing merry parents sharing red wine under the moonlight outside in my mother’s garden, like I’m used to while eating Manchego cheese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of Monday was basically slept away; thanks to a mixture of leftover jet lag and this sickness.
We ended the day with a delicious dinner by the best (American) chef in Spain, Señor Kuhl!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09132017/pasta.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pasta agliolio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan has mastered pasta algliolio from the movie Chef, thanks to this video from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bJUiWdM__Qw&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re wondering what our kitchen here looks like, wonder no more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09132017/kitchen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan in Kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kitchen is minimalistic. Two electric stove top ranges sit on a counter beside the sink, and underneath you find the washing machine (no, not the dishwasher). To the left of that is the junior refrigerator. Junior because it’s larger than a mini-fridge yet smaller than a full grown fridge. There’s also a microwave, above the fridge. And no oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooking in this mini-malistic kitchen has been more feasible than anticipated. The limited storage forces us to buy fresher ingredients, and not just boxed foods. The abundance of fresh produce markets and their walkability makes it easy to grab only what we need and not overbuy. The actual cooking is also not terrible. You’d think that going from 4 to 2 ranges would take some getting used to. However, if you aren’t meal prepping and are cooking for two, then it’s actually the perfect stove top size. &lt;del&gt;Ryan disagrees with this.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I wonder if you suddenly left everything you’re accustomed to behind and had to adapt to a life with less, would you find out what truly brings you joy? Sometimes simpler is better. This time, I can confirm. Cooking in this kitchenette is like a breath of fresh air. Would it be different if we weren’t on vacation? Maybe. Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did splurge on some flan. Because like I said, we have no oven; and proper flan requires an oven to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09132017/flan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flan box&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Til next time compadres! :wave:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09132017/dorn_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dorn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="sangria" /><category term="cooking" /><summary type="html">I apologize for the use of the third person in that title, I know I’m not Elmo. I’m keeping this one short because not much happened over the past two days due to a nasty cold I acquired.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where Ryan Becomes King of the South</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/11/the-one-where-ryan-becomes-king-of-the-south" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where Ryan Becomes King of the South" /><published>2017-09-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/11/the-one-where-ryan-becomes-king-of-the-south</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/11/the-one-where-ryan-becomes-king-of-the-south">&lt;p&gt;Before I get to that, I have to tell you about this delicious Spanish wine called Moscatel. It’s a rich and syrupy, Sherry-like wine, made from Moscatel grapes. It tastes of molasses and happiness. Normally, sweet dessert wine is not our thing. But we had met two friendly locals, Jeronimo and Geoffrey, and were accompanying them for a drink (or two).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/wine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moscatel wine barrel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the Moscatel is served in small glasses to sip just like Sherry. They also served Pajarete, another wine found in Malaga, and Vermouth. All three are poured out of small wine barrels. I wish I had taken more pictures of the place, but have no fear, I’ll make sure to take more when we return (we plan to go back soon!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to learn more about our new friends over a night of sipping wine and beers. Jero, is a young Argentinian now living in Spain for 16 years; and Geoffrey (pronounced Jeffrey, who we had now nicknamed Jefe) is a fellow American from Oregon. Soon it was 6:30 in the morning and we were ready for bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we woke up at 2pm refreshed and ready to see more of Malaga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/lazy_phone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny holding phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to venture out to Castillo de Gibralfaro, a Moorish castle that sits atop a hill overlooking Malaga and the Mediterranean sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/malaga_port.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Port of Malaga&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/malaga_city_overlook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bull Stadium&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the No. 35 bus up to the castle since we were feeling &lt;del&gt;lazy&lt;/del&gt; smart. It felt as if we were in an episode of Game of Thrones, in a Dornish fortress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/castle_steps.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Castle Steps&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/castle_pines.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Castle trees&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, Ryan made his claim to the throne and became King of the South.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/ryan_on_castle_pathway.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan in castle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, he didn’t realize that he might not fit in his new castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/ryan_not_fitting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan not fitting in castle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09112017/sara_in_castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sara fitting in castle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="wine" /><summary type="html">Before I get to that, I have to tell you about this delicious Spanish wine called Moscatel. It’s a rich and syrupy, Sherry-like wine, made from Moscatel grapes. It tastes of molasses and happiness. Normally, sweet dessert wine is not our thing. But we had met two friendly locals, Jeronimo and Geoffrey, and were accompanying them for a drink (or two).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where We Bought Bad Cheese</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/09/the-one-where-we-bought-the-bad-cheese" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We Bought Bad Cheese" /><published>2017-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/09/the-one-where-we-bought-the-bad-cheese</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/09/the-one-where-we-bought-the-bad-cheese">&lt;p&gt;We made it to Malaga Friday morning after a short flight from Barcelona. Ryan was awestruck by the floor cleaning techniques at the Barcelona airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3ov9k0ap6XEgjUoplC/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Gif Of Lady Zooming By&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penny got to ride outside her carrier for all but five minutes of the flight. Here she is begging to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/penny_in_carrier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny in carrier on airplane&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, she doesn’t make a peep, but I’m guessing she couldn’t contain her excitement either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we got into Malaga before the Airbnb was ready, we dropped our bags off and headed for a stroll around town. We found out that Churros y Chocolate are as prominent in Malaga as Starbucks in a college town. Clearly, we had to stop for some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/churro_time.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Churro Time&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few times does a plan go so perfectly for non-Type A people, such as us, that we must pat ourselves on the back. So far, this was the whole trip here but the cherry on top is finding our Airbnb. Look at this beauty. Here is Ryan again for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/ryan_apartment.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan in apartment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s even got Penny’s seal of approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/penny_on_couch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny on couch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were settled into the apartment, we decided to go back out to get our bearings down. We walked to Old Town and noticed most stores were closed and not a lot of people were out and about. It was too early in the day for siesta, and just another Friday. We thought maybe it was a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/empty_promenade.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Empty town promenade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were correct. The town of Malaga was celebrating their patron saint, the Santa Maria de la Victoria, credited by King Ferdinand for winning back the city from the Moors in 1487. We encountered the long procession where the (massive) statue is carried back to the cathedral at night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/packed_promenade(1).jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Packed town promenade&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we walked to el Mercado de Atarazanas, after my dad’s suggestions of the market from a Youtube video. There we found fresh seafood (mariscos), vegetables (verduras), y queso Manchego. Also a TON of Marcona almonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/almonds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;So many almonds!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I snatched up some Manchego cheese and jamon Iberico with much excitement. The cheese cost € 4 and I was pumped for this treat to my palate. We had an early dinner to include the cheese. And to much dissatisfaction, I found out that either I had bought the wrong cheese, or this was the real version of Spanish Manchego that I now had to adapt to. It was very similar to blue cheese and I don’t know about you, but that’s where I draw the line on my love of queso. Something about that awful sour mold taste is not appealing. I’m just glad we didn’t drop € 15 on that bad boy. This is how you travel though, throwing caution to the wind. Like that time I bought a whole wedge of unpasteurized cheese in London, without ever having had something so dangerous and unregulated, and didn’t die! Wouldn’t be writing this if I had…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/09092017/manchego.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Manchego Cheese&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html">We made it to Malaga Friday morning after a short flight from Barcelona. Ryan was awestruck by the floor cleaning techniques at the Barcelona airport.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The One Where We Get to Spain</title><link href="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We Get to Spain" /><published>2017-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://fiveweeksabroad.com/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain">&lt;p&gt;The incredible forces of jetlag have me writing this at 3:42am on this fine Friday morning. This is after having stared at the ceiling of our tiny hotel room for 2 hrs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Spain unscathed after the hottest plane ride of my life. Something about that stale airplane air, the hundreds of bodies surrounding us, and Penny’s body heat made for an uncomfortable flight. Someday we’ll fly in the comfort of First or Business class; but what’s flying to Europe without making you work for it?  After eleven hours from Los Angeles we landed in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully getting into Spain with Penny was surprisingly simple. Once through border patrol, we had a quick examination of Penny’s health certificate and a scan of her ID chip and she was cleared to go. We picked up our bags and grabbed a taxi to the hotel.
Our tiny hotel room in Barcelona. Okay, so this demands photographic evidence to really show how small this room is. Conveniently, I’ve got my handy-dandy 6 foot 4 hubby for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogTiny1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Hotel Room 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogTiny2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Hotel Room 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we’re only here for a night. We had to fly direct from the US into Spain in order to get Penny in the cabin with us, through the fabulous Norwegian Airlines (more on this in a future post). So that left flying into Barcelona for far less than directly into Malaga or Madrid. Anyway, we will be getting to our destination in Malaga later today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there isn’t much to say about Barcelona considering our short stay here. We arrived deliriously jetlagged, hungry and in great need of a shower. Once we got our needs sorted, we went out to find some dinner. The hotel is right off the now infamous Las Ramblas street; which we walked down to find some tapas in the form of meatballs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/Blogmeatballs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meatballs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some delicious Spanish fusion meatballs, we tackled a light drizzle back to the hotel. Penny then had the LONGEST pee ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/Blogpee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny Pee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her poor bladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only place you might find a mere essence of happiness at LAX is within the Tom Bradley International Terminal. Ryan and I first experienced this beautiful terminal thanks to a flight to MIA that had an international connection to Heathrow. Finally, we were more than plebeians trudging along the horrid TSA line; we had found mecca. And now we were back! This time with Priority Pass lounge access via Chase Sapphire!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogLounge1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Access&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penny ate the finest mediocre sushi and enjoyed views of the sheeple down below. Did I mention they had an unattended bar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogLounge2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Drinks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of Ferris Bueller, “It’s so choice. If you have the means, I highly recommend picking one up.” Of course, he’s talking about a vintage Ferrari and I’m referencing a piece of plastic with amazing travel bonuses– but, to each their own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><summary type="html">The incredible forces of jetlag have me writing this at 3:42am on this fine Friday morning. This is after having stared at the ceiling of our tiny hotel room for 2 hrs…</summary></entry></feed>
