<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-09T10:00:32+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Five Weeks Abroad</title><subtitle>Life in a new place... for a little while</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The One Where We Get to Spain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The One Where We Get to Spain" /><published>2017-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/the-one-where-we-get-to-spain">&lt;p&gt;The incredible forces of jetlag have me writing this at 3:42am on this fine Friday morning. This is after having stared at the ceiling of our tiny hotel room for 2 hrs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Spain unscathed after the hottest plane ride of my life. Something about that stale airplane air, the hundreds of bodies surrounding us, and Penny’s body heat made for an uncomfortable flight. Someday we’ll fly in the comfort of First or Business class; but what’s flying to Europe without making you work for it?  After eleven hours from Los Angeles we landed in Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully getting into Spain with Penny was surprisingly simple. Once through border patrol, we had a quick examination of Penny’s health certificate and a scan of her ID chip and she was cleared to go. We picked up our bags and grabbed a taxi to the hotel.
Our tiny hotel room in Barcelona. Okay, so this demands photographic evidence to really show how small this room is. Conveniently, I’ve got my handy-dandy 6 foot 4 hubby for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogTiny1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Hotel Room 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogTiny2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Hotel Room 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we’re only here for a night. We had to fly direct from the US into Spain in order to get Penny in the cabin with us, through the fabulous Norwegian Airlines (more on this in a future post). So that left flying into Barcelona for far less than directly into Malaga or Madrid. Anyway, we will be getting to our destination in Malaga later today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there isn’t much to say about Barcelona considering our short stay here. We arrived deliriously jetlagged, hungry and in great need of a shower. Once we got our needs sorted, we went out to find some dinner. The hotel is right off the now infamous Las Ramblas street; which we walked down to find some tapas in the form of meatballs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/Blogmeatballs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meatballs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some delicious Spanish fusion meatballs, we tackled a light drizzle back to the hotel. Penny then had the LONGEST pee ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/Blogpee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penny Pee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her poor bladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only place you might find a mere essence of happiness at LAX is within the Tom Bradley International Terminal. Ryan and I first experienced this beautiful terminal thanks to a flight to MIA that had an international connection to Heathrow. Finally, we were more than plebeians trudging along the horrid TSA line; we had found mecca. And now we were back! This time with Priority Pass lounge access via Chase Sapphire!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogLounge1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Access&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penny ate the finest mediocre sushi and enjoyed views of the sheeple down below. Did I mention they had an unattended bar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/fiveweeksabroad/BlogLounge2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lounge Drinks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of Ferris Bueller, “It’s so choice. If you have the means, I highly recommend picking one up.” Of course, he’s talking about a vintage Ferrari and I’m referencing a piece of plastic with amazing travel bonuses– but, to each their own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saralee Morales</name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="spain" /><summary type="html">The incredible forces of jetlag have me writing this at 3:42am on this fine Friday morning. This is after having stared at the ceiling of our tiny hotel room for 2 hrs…</summary></entry></feed>